thebrowser.com 2012-10-21

# Privacy Policy | The Browser

(last update: Feb 2012)

**Information we gather**

The following information is gathered from our website visitors and app users:  
IP address  
Email address (when registering).  
As appropriate, you may be asked to enter your e-mail address. You may, however, use our app and site services anonymously (with limited functionality).  
We do not ask for, use or store your credit card or other payment information; billing is performed via external billing services (such as iTunes) and we do not have access to your payment information during the process. 

**How we use the information we gather**

We use the information to enhance your visitor experience and to provide your subscription service across web, iOS apps and other media.   
As a subscriber to our services, you may receive related product or service information via email, notifications about technical issues with the service, maintenance periods etc.   
In addition, if you decide to opt-in to receiving our email newsletter, we will send you periodic emails with information from the site (the email address you provide will only be used to send you information and site updates). More information about our newsletters can be found [here](http://thebrowser.com/newsletters).  
Please note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

**The people that are given access to this information**

Your personal information is accessible by server administrator, and by our marketing department.

Your nickname may be displayed in non-protected contexts on the site, and will be visible if you choose to share your reading list with others. 

**The security measures we have in place to protect your personal information**

To safeguard your personal information, we use SSL encryption between your computer and our server, and we keep all server software secure by applying all necessary security patches.  
Whenever you provide sensitive information, we will take all reasonable steps to protect it, such as encrypting it during transmission and processing. We will also take reasonable security measures to protect your personal information in storage.  
We use proactive system monitoring to detect suspicious activities. 

**Our use of cookies**

Our website makes use of cookies which are small digital files that are stored in your web browser that enable us to track your return visits to our website.   
Your browser settings may allow you to block these cookies, but we recommend you have them enabled to help us personalise your experience of our website.  
Additionally, 3rd party advertisers on our site may use cookies for tracking purposes.  
Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads.  
Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to visitors based on their visit to sites they visit on the Internet.  
Website visitors may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

**Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third party links**

As a part of our recommendation service, we include links to third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

**Your Consent**

By using our site, you consent to our privacy policy.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy please email feedback[at]thebrowser[dot]com.
